<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
     
    <page filename="Hamlet.028v.tif" pagination="56" signature="III.4" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
        <!-- Marginalia --> 	<!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->
        <marginalia>
            <language ident="EN">
                <position place="left_margin" book_orientation="0">
                    <marginalia_text>   
                        Ring
                    </marginalia_text>
                </position>
            </language>
        </marginalia>      
        
        <!-- Substitutions -->
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            Lay not that flattering unction to your soul, |
            That not your trespass but my madness speaks; |
            It will but skin and film the ulcerous place, |
            Whiles rank corruption mining all within |
            Infects unseen: confess your self to heaven, |
            Repent what’s past, avoid what is to come, |
            &quot; And do not spread the compost on the weeds |
            &quot; To make them ranker: forgive me this my vertue, |
            &quot; For in the fatness of these pursie times |
            &quot; Vertue it self of vice must pardon beg, |
            &quot; Yea curb and wooe for leave to do him good." 
            
            amendedText="Lay not that flattering unction to your soul, |
            That not your trespass, but my madness, speaks: |
            It will but skin and film the ulcerous place; |
            Whilst rank corruption, mining all within, |
            Infects unseen: confess your self to heaven; |
            Repent what’s past, avoid what is to come."/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            Then throw away the worser part of it, |
            And leave the purer with the other half. |
            Goodnight, but go not to my Uncles bed, |
            Assume a vertue if you have it not. Once more goodnight. |
            &quot; That monster custom, who all sense doth eat, |
            &quot; of habits devil, is Angel yet in this, |
            &quot; That to the use of actions fair and good |
            &quot; He likewise gives a frock or livery |
            &quot; That aptly is put on: refrain to night, |
            &quot; And that shall lend a kind of easiness |
            &quot; To the next abstinence, the next more easy; |
            &quot; For use almost can change the stamp of nature, |
            &quot; And master the Devil, or throw him out |
            &quot; With wondrous potency: Once more, good night, |
            And when you are desirous to be blest |
            I’ll blessing beg of you, for this same Lord |
            I do repent, but heaven hath pleas'd it so, |
            To punish me with this, and this with me, |
            That I must be their scourge and minister |
            I will bestow him and will answer well |
            The death I gave him; so again good night. |
            I must be cruel only to be kind, |
            Thus bad begins and worse remains behind. |
            One word more good lady" 
            
            amendedText="Then throw away the worser part of it. |
            And live the purer with the other half. |
            Goodnight; but go not to my Uncles bed: |
            Assume a vertue, if you have it not. Once more goodnight! |
            And when you are desirous to be blest, |
            I’ll blessing beg of you;--for this same Lord, |
            I do repent: but heaven hath pleas'd it so, |
            To punish me with this, and this with me. |
            I will bestow him and will answer well |
            The death I gave him; so again good night! |
            I must be cruel only to be kind; |
            Thus bad begins, and worse remains behind.-- |
            One word more good lady"/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            &quot; Ham. Not this by no means that I bid you do, |
            Let not the King tempt you to bed again, |
            &quot; Pinch wanton on your cheek, call you his Mouse, |
            &quot; And let him for a pair of reechy kisses, |
            &quot;Or padling in your neck with his damn'd fingers, |
            Make you to ravel all this matter out, |
            That I essentially am not in madness," 
            
            amendedText="
            Ham. Let not the King tempt you to bed again; |
            Make you to ravel all this matter out, |
            That I essentially am not in madness,"/>

        
    </annotation>
</transcription>