<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
    
    <page filename="Hamlet.018v.tif" pagination="36" signature="II.2" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
        <!-- Marginalia --> 	<!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->
        
        <!-- Substitutions -->
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            Had he the motive, and that for passion |
            That I have? he would &quot; drown the stage with tears, |
            &quot; And cleave the general ear with horrid speech, |
            Make mad the guilty and appeal the free, |
            &quot; Confound the ignorant, and amaze indeed, |
            &quot; The very faculties of eyes and ears, yet I, |
            &quot; A dull and muddy metled raskal, peak |
            &quot; Like John a dreams, unpregrant of my cause, |
            &quot; And can say nothing, no not for a King, |
            &quot; Upon whose property and most dear life |
            &quot; A damn'd defeat was made: am I a coward? |
            &quot; Who calls me villain, breaks my pate across, |
            &quot; Plucks off my bear, and blows it in my face, |
            &quot; Twekes me by th' nose gives me the lye i'th throat |
            &quot; As deep as to the lungs? who does me this? |
            &quot; Hah? s'wounds I should take it, for it cannot be |
            But I am pigeon liver'd, and lack gall |
            To make oppression bitter or e're this |
            I should have fatted all the region Kites |
            With this slaves offal: &quot; bloody, bawdy villain, |
            &quot; Remorsless, treacherous lecherous, kindless villian. |
            &quot; Why what an ass am I? this most brave, |
            &quot; That I the son of a dear father murthered, |
            &quot; Prompted to my revenge by heaven and hell, |
            &quot; Must like a whore unpack my heart with words, |
            &quot; And fall a cursing like a very drab, stallion, fie upon't. foh |
            &quot; About my brains, &quot; hum, I have heard |
            That guilty creatures sitting at a Play |
            Have by the very cunning of the Scene |
            Been strook so to the soul, that presently |
            They have proclaim'd their malefactions: |
            For murther though it have no tongue will speak |
            &quot; With most miraculous organ. &quot; I'll have these Players |
            Play something like the murther of my father |
            Before mine Uncle: I'll observe his looks, |
            &quot; I'll tent him to the quick, if he do blench |
            &quot; I know my course. &quot; The spirit that I have seen |
            May be a Devil, and the Devil hath power |
            T assume a pleasing shape, &quot; yea and perhaps |
            &quot; Out of my weakness and my melancholly, |
            &quot; As he is very potent with such spirits, |
            &quot; Abuses me to damn me: &quot; I'll have grounds |
            More relative than this, the Play's the thing |
            Wherein I'll catch the conscience of the King." 
          
            amendedText="Had he the motive, and that cause for passion, |
            That I have? he would &quot; drown the stage with tears, |
            Make mad the guilty, and appall the free; |
            &quot; Confound the ignorant, and amaze, indeed, |
            &quot; The very faculties of eyes and ears, |
            But I am pigeon liver'd, and lack gall |
            To make oppression bitter; or, e're this, |
            I should have fatted all the region Kites |
            With this slaves offal: I have heard, |
            That guilty creatures, sitting at a Play, |
            Have by the very cunning of the Scene |
            Been strook so to the soul, that presently |
            They have proclaim'd their malefactions: |
            For murther, though it have no tongue, will speak |
            &quot; With most miraculous organ. &quot; I'll have these Players |
            Play something like the murther of my father, |
            Before mine Uncle: I'll observe his looks; |
            &quot; I'll tent him to the quick; if he look pale, |
            &quot; I know my course. &quot; The spirit that I have seen |
            May be a Devil, and the Devil may have power |
            T assume a pleasing shape. I will have grounds |
            More relative than this: the Play's the thing, |
            Wherein I'll catch the conscience of the King."/>
        
        
    </annotation>
</transcription>
