<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
    
    <page filename="Hamlet.017r.tif" pagination="33" signature="II.2" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
        <!-- Marginalia --> 	<!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->
        
        <marginalia anchor_text="french Faulkeners">
            <language ident="EN">
                <position place="left_margin" book_orientation="0">
                    <marginalia_text>
                        =ly <!-- Possible different hand -->
                    </marginalia_text>
                </position>
            </language>
        </marginalia>
        
        <marginalia anchor_text="&quot; Old grandsire Priam seeks; so proceed you.">
            <language ident="EN">
                <position place="left_margin" book_orientation="0">
                    <marginalia_text>
                        In
                    </marginalia_text>
                </position>
            </language>
        </marginalia>
        <marginalia anchor_text="&quot; Old grandsire Priam seeks; so proceed you.">
            <language ident="EN">
                <position place="right_margin" book_orientation="0">
                    <marginalia_text>
                        In
                    </marginalia_text>
                </position>
            </language>
        </marginalia>
        
        <!-- Substitutions -->
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="&quot; Ham. Why, as by lot, God wot, and then you know, it came to
            &quot; pass, as most like it was: &quot; the first row of the Rubrick will
            shew you more, for look whore my abridgement comes." 
                                                             
            amendedText="Ham. the first row of Rubrick will
            shew you more, for, look, whore my abridgement comes."/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="Ham. You are welcome masters, welcome all, &quot; I am glad to see
            &quot; thee well, welcome good friends; quot; oh old friend ! why thy face
            is valanc'd since I saw thee last, come'st thou to beard me in
            Denmark? what my young Lady and Mistriss! my Lady, your Ladiship
            is nearer to heaven than when I saw you last by the altitude of a
            Chopine, I wish your voice, like a piece of uncurrant gold, but not
            crackt within the ring: masters you are all welcome, we'll e'en to't
            like friendly Faulkeners, fly at any thing we see, we'll have a speech
            strait, come give us a taste of your quality, come a passionate
            peech."
            
            amendedText="Ham. You are welcome masters, welcome all; oh my old friend ! thy face
            is valanc'd since I saw thee last: come'st thou to beard me in
            Denmark? what! my young Lady and Mistriss? marry, your Ladiship
            is grown nearer to heaven than when I saw you last by the altitude of a
            Chiopine, I wish your voice, like a piece of uncurrant gold, but not
            crackt within the ring -- come, we'll e'en to't
            like french Faulkeners, fly at any thing we see; we'll have a speech
            strait. come give us a taste of your quality, come a passionate
            speech."/>
        
       <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="Ham. I heard thee speak me a speech once, but it was never
           acted, or if it was, not above once, for the Play I remember pleased 
           not the million, 'twas a caviary to the general, &quot; but it was as I
           &quot; received it and others, whole judgements in such matters cried in
           &quot; the top of mine, and excellent Play, well digested in the Scenes, set
           &quot; down with as much modesty as cunning. I remember one said
           &quot; there were no sallets in the lines to make the matter savoury, nor
           &quot; no matter in the phrase that might indite the author of affection,
           &quot; but call'd it an honest method, as wholesome as sweet, and by very
           &quot; much more handsome that fine; &quot; one speech in 't I chiefly loved,
           'twas Aeneas talk to Dido, and thereabout of it especially when he
           speaks of Priams daughter, if it live in your memory begin at this
           line, let me see, let me see, the rugged Pyrrhus, like th'Hircanian Beast,
           'tis not it begins with Pyrrhus. The rugged Pyrrhus, he whose sable arms," 
           
           amendedText="Ham. I heard thee speak me a speech once, but it was never
           acted: or if it was, not above once; for the Play I remember, pleased 
           not the million, 'twas caviar to the general; one speech in it I chiefly loved;
           'twas Aeneas tale to Dido; and thereabout of it especially, where he
           speaks of Priams daughter. if it live in your memory, begin at this
           line, let me see, let me see - the rugged Pyrrhus, like th'Hircanian Beast - best, best, no,
           thats not it yet it begins with Pyrrhus. The rugged Pyrrhus, he whose sable arms,"/>
        
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            Black as his purpose did the night resemble,
            &quot; When he lay couched in th' ominous horse, |
            &quot; Hath now his dread and black complexion smear'd |
            &quot; With Heraldry more dismal head to foot: |
            &quot; Now is he total Gules, horridly trickt |
            &quot; With blood of fathers, mothers, daughters, sons, |
            &quot; Bak'd and embasted with parching streets, |
            &quot; That lend a tyrannous and a damned light |
            &quot; To their Lords murder, roasted in wrath and fire, |
            &quot; And thus o're-cised with coagulate gore, |
            &quot; With eyes like Carbuncles, the hellish Pyrrus |
            &quot; Old grandfire Priam seeks; so proceed you." 
            
            amendedText="Black as his purpose did the night resemble;--"/>
                        
        <!-- Symbols and marks -->	<!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->
        <symbol name="Hatching" place="right_margin"/> 
        
    </annotation>
</transcription>


