<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
    
    <page filename="Hamlet.034r.tif" pagination="68" signature="IV.6" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
        <!-- Marginalia --> 	<!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->
        
        <marginalia>
            <language ident="EN">
                <position place="left_margin" book_orientation="90">
                    <marginalia_text>
                        Hamlet prince of Denmark
                    </marginalia_text>
                    <person name="Hamlet"/>
                </position>
            </language>
        </marginalia>
        
     
        
        
        <!-- Substitutions -->
        <substitution method="pen" type="deletion" copyText="Ham. Being thus be-netted round with villains, |
            E're I could make a Prologue to my brains |
            They had begun the Play: I sate me down, |
            Devis'd a new Commission, wrote it fair: |
            I once did hold it, as our Statists do, |
            A baseness to write fair and labour'd much |
            How to forget that learning; but Sir now |
            It did me Yeomans service: wilt thou know |
            Th' effect of what I wrote? |
            Hor. I good my lord. |
            Ham. An earnest conjuration from the king, |
            As England was his faithful tributary, |
            As love between them like the Palm might flourish, |
            As peace should still her wheaten garland wear, |
            '' And stand a Comma 'tween their amities, |
            '' And many such-like, as Sir of great charge, |
            That on the view of these contents, |
            Without debatement further, more or less, |
            He should the bearers put to sudden death, |
            Not shriving-time allow'd. |
            Hor. How was this seal'd? |
            Ham. Why, even in that was heaven ordinant. |
            I had my father's signet in my purse, |
            Which was the model of that Danish Seal: |
            Folded the writ up in the form of th' other, |
            Subscrib'd it, gave th' impression, plac'd it safely, |
            The changling never known, now the next day |
            Was our Sea-fight; and what to this was sequent |
            Thou know'st already. |
            Hor. So Guildenstern and Rosencrantz go to't. |
            Ham. They are not near my conscience, their defeat |
            Does by their own insinuation grow; |
            '' 'Tis dangerous when the baser nature comes |
            '' Between the pass and fell incensed point. |
            '' Of mighty opposites. |
            Hor. Why, what a king is this! |
            Ham. Does it not, think you, stand me now upon? |
            He that hath kill'd my King, and whored my mother, |
            Stept in between th' election and my hopes, |
            Thrown out his angle for my proper life, |
            And with such cozenage; is't not perfect conscience?" amendedText=""/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="Enter a Courtier." amendedText="Enter Ostrick"/>
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="Court." amendedText="Ostr."/>
        
        <symbol name="Hatching" place="left_margin"/
        
        
    </annotation>
</transcription>