<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
     
    <page filename="Hamlet.031r.tif" pagination="61" signature="IV.3-IV.4" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
      
        <!-- Scene change: IV.3 - IV.4 -->
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="deletion" copyText="
            &quot; Since yet thy cicatrice looks raw and red |
            &quot; After the Danish Sword, and thy free awe |
            &quot; Pays homage to us, thou maist not coldly set |
            &quot; Our Sovereign process, which imports at full |
            &quot; By Letters congruing to that effect |
            &quot; The present death of Hamlet, do it, England, |
            &quot; For like the Hectick in my blood he rages, |
            &quot; And thou must cure me: till I know 'tis done, |
            &quot; How e'er my haps, my joys will ne'er begin.  [Exit. |
            
            Enter Fortinbras with his Army over the Stage. |
            
            &quot; Fort. Go Captain, from me greet the Danish King. |
            &quot; Tell him that by his license Fortinbrass |
            &quot; Craves the conveyance of a promis'd march |
            &quot; Over his Kingdom; you know the rendezvous, |
            &quot; If that his Majesty would aught with us |
            &quot; We shall express our duty in his eye, |
            &quot; And let him know so. |
            &quot; Capt. I will do't my Lord. |
            &quot; Fort. Go softly on. |
            
            Enter Hamlet, Rosencraus, &amp;c. |
            
            &quot; Ham. Good Sir whose powers are these? |
            &quot; Capt. They are of Norway Sir. |
            &quot; Ham. How propos'd Sir I pray you? |
            &quot; Capt. Against some part of Poland. |
            &quot; Ham. Who commands them Sir? |
            &quot; Capt. The Nephew of old Norway, Fortinbrass. |
            &quot; Ham. Goes it against the main of Poland Sir, |
            &quot; Or for some frontier? |
            &quot; Capt. Truly to speak, and with no addition, |
            &quot; We go to gain a little patch of ground |
            &quot; That hath in it no profit but the name, |
            &quot; To pay five duckets, five I would not farm it, |
            &quot; Nor will it yield to Norway or the Pole |
            &quot; A ranker rate, should it be sold in fee. |
            &quot; Ham. Why, then, the Pollock never will defend it. |
            &quot; Capt. Yes, it is already garrison'd. |
            &quot; Ham. Two thousand souls, and 20000 duckets |
            &quot; Will not debate the question of this straw; |
            &quot; This is th' imposthume of much wealth and peace, |
            &quot; That inward breaks and shews no cause without |
            &quot; Why the man dies. I humbly thank you Sir. |
            &quot; Ham. God b'w'ye Sir. |
            &quot; Ros. Wil't please you go my Lord? |
            &quot; Ham. I'll be with you straight, go a little before.
            " amendedText=""/>
       
        
    </annotation>
</transcription>

