<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
    
    <page filename="Hamlet.021v.tif" pagination="42" signature="III.2" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
        <!-- Marginalia -->     <!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->

        <marginalia>
            <language ident="EN">
                <position place="left_margin" book_orientation="0">
                    <marginalia_text>
                        (6)
                        King
                        Queen
                        Polonius
                        Ophelia
                        Guildenstern
                        Rosencraus
                        Attendants
                        Flourish
                        Throne
                        Chaire
                    </marginalia_text>
                    <person name="King"/>
                    <person name="Queen"/>
                    <person name="Polonius"/>
                    <person name="Ophelia"/>
                    <person name="Guildenstern"/>
                    <person name="Rosencraus"/>
                    <person name="Attendants"/>
                    <person name="Flourish"/>
                    <person name="Throne"/>
                </position>
            </language>
        </marginalia>
        
        <!-- Substitutions -->
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            &quot; the mirror up to nature; to show virtue her own feature, scorn her own
            &quot; image, and the very age and body of the time his form and pressure:
            &quot; now this over-done, or come tardy of, though it makes the
            &quot; unskilful laugh, cannot but make the judicious grieve; the censure
            &quot; of which one must in your allowance o'erweigh a whole Theatre 
            &quot; of others. O there be Players that I have seen play, and heard
            &quot; others praise, and that highly, not to speak it profanely, that
            &quot; neither having the accent of Christians, nor the gait of Christian, 
            &quot; Pagan, nor man, have so strutted and bellowed, that I have thought 
            &quot; some of Natures journey-men had made men, and not made them
            &quot; well, they imitated humanity so abominably. 
            &quot; Play. I hope we have reformed that indifferently with us.
            &quot; Ham. O reform it altogether, and let those that play your
            &quot; Clowns speak no more than is set down for them, for there be of
            &quot; them that will themselves laugh, to set on some quantity of barren
            &quot; spectators to laugh too, though in the mean time some necessary
            &quot; question of the Play be then to be considered: that's villanous,
            &quot; and shews a most pitiful ambition in the Fool that uses it: go,
            &quot; make you ready, &quot; How now my Lord? will the King hear this
            piece of work?
            " amendedText="Ha: - How now, my Lord? wil the King hear this
            piece of work?"/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="deletion" copyText="Enter Polonius, Guildenstern, and Rosencraus" amendedText="Polonius, Guildenstern, and Rosencraus"/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="Ros. I my Lord." amendedText="Both. We will my Lord."/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="insertion" copyText="[Exeunt those two." amendedText="[Exeunt those two. &amp; Polonius."/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="Ham. hat ho, Horatio?" amendedText="Ham. What, ho, Horatio!"/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="insertion" copyText="Ham, Horatio, thou are e'en as just a man 
            As e're my conversation met withal." amendedText="Ham, Horatio, thou are e'en as just a man,
            As e're my conversation met withal."/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            Ham. Nay, do not think I flatter, |
            For what advancement may I hope from thee |
            That hast no revenue but thy good spirits |
            To feed and cloath thee? why should the poor be flattered? |
            &quot; No, let the candid tongue lick absurd pomp, |
            &quot; And crook the pregnant hinges of the knee |
            &quot; Where thrift may follow fawning, doest thou hear? |
            Since my dear soul was Mistress of her choice, |
            And could of men distinguish her election, |
            Sh'ath seal'd thee for her self: for thou hast been |
            As one in suffering all that suffers nothing;
            &quot; A man that fortunes buffets and rewards |
            &quot; Hast ta'n with equal thanks: and blest are those |
            &quot; Whose blood and judgment are so well commedled, |
            &quot; That they are not a pipe for fortunes finger, 
            " 
            
            amendedText="
            Ham. Nay, do not think I flatter: |
            For what advancement may I hope from thee? |
            why should the poor be flattered? |
            Since my dear soul was Mistress of her choice, |
            And could of men distinguish, her election, |
            Hath seal'd thee for her self: for thou hast been |
            As one, in suffering all, that suffers nothing:
            "/>
            
        
        <!-- Symbols and marks -->    <!-- Positions available: head, intext, tail, left_margin, right_margin -->
        <symbol name="Hatching" place="right_margin" text="[Enter Horatio."/> 
        <symbol name="Hatching" place="intext" text="[Enter Horatio."/>
        
        
        
    </annotation>
</transcription>
