<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>

<!DOCTYPE transcription SYSTEM "http://www.livesandletters.ac.uk/schema/aor_20141023.dtd">

<transcription xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ChrisRG/ReadingHamlet/master/RHschema.xsd">
    
    <page filename="Hamlet.038r.tif" pagination="75" signature="V.1" reader="John Ward"/> <!-- Signature = act + scene -->
    <annotation>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            Ham. There's another. Why may not that be the skull of a lawyer? 
            where be his quiddities now, his quilities, his cases, his tenures, 
            and his tricks? why does he suffer this mad knave now to knock 
            him about the sconce with a dirty shovel, and will not tell him of 
            his actions of battery? hum, this fellow might be in's time a great 
            buyer of land, with his statutes, his recognisances, his fines, his 
            double vouchers, his recoveries, to have his fine pate full of fine 
            dirt: will vouchers vouch him no more of his purchases and doubles, 
            than the length and bredth of a pair of Indentures? the very
            conveyances of his land will scarcely lie in this box, and must th' 
            inheritor himself have no more, ha? |
            Hora. Not a jot more, my lord. |
            Ham. &quot; Is not parchment made of sheepskins? |
            Hora. &quot; I my Lord, and of calve-skins too. |
            Ham. &quot; They are sheep and calves which seek out assurance in 
            that. &quot; I will speak to this fellow: Whose grave’s this sirrah? |
            Clow. Mine Sir, or a pit of clay for to be made. |
            Ham. I think it's thine indeed, for thou ly'st in't. |
            Clow. You lye out on 't Sir, and therefore 'tis not yours: for my
            part I do not lye in't, yet it is mine.
            Ham. Thou doest lye in't, to be in't and say it is thine, 'tis for the 
            dead, not for the quick, therefore thou lyest." 
            
            amendedText="
            Ham. There's another: Why may not that be the skull of a lawyer? 
            where be his quiddities now? his quiliets? his cases? his tenures, 
            and his tricks? why does he suffer this mad knave now to knock 
            him about the sconce with a dirty shovel, and will not tell him of 
            his actions of battery? 
            I will speak to this fellow: Whose grave’s this sirrah? |
            Clow. Mine Sir-or a pit of clay for to be made.-- |
            Ham. I think, it's thine indeed; for thou ly'st in't. |
            Clow. You lye out on 't Sir, and therefore 'tis not yours: for my
            part I do not lye in't, yet it is mine.
            Ham. Thou doest lye in't, to be in't, and say, it is thine; 'tis for the 
            dead, not for the quick, therefore thou lyest."/>
        
        <substitution method="pen" type="replacement" copyText="
            How absolute the knave is, we must speak by the card, or 
            equivocation will undo us. Horatio this three years I have took 
            notice of it, the age is grown so picked, that the toe of the Pesant comes 
            so near the heel of the Courtier, he galls his kibe. How long hast 
            thou been a Grave-maker?" amendedText="
            How absolute the knave is? we must speak by the card, or 
            equivocation will undo us. Horatio these three years I have took 
            notice, that the toe of the Pesant comes 
            so near the heel of the Courtier, he galls his kibe. How long hast 
            thou been a Grave-maker?"/>

        <substitution method="pen" type="insertion" copyText="
            Ham. I marry, why was he sent into England?" amendedText="
            Ham. I, marry, why was he sent into England?"/>
            
            
            
    </annotation>
</transcription>
